Thomas M. Rivers Papers 1887-1963 Mss.B.R52
American Philosophical Society
Thomas M. Rivers Papers
1887-1963
Mss.B.R52
American Philosophical Society
10.0 Linear feet
The bacteriologist and virologist Thomas Milton Rivers spent over thirty years at the Rockefeller Institute as a researcher in the Department of Bacteriology and from 1937-1955, as Director. Working on measles and pneumonia, Rivers discovered the parainfluenzae bacillus and cultivated vaccine virus for human use, and during the 1950s, he played an important role in coordinating research on poliomyelitis as head of the National Institute for Infantile Paralysis. During the Second World War, Rivers led the Naval Medical Research Unit in the South Pacific, rising to the rank of Rear Admiral. The Rivers Papers contains correspondence, laboratory notes, speeches, and photographs documenting Rivers' activities at the Rockefeller Institute, the development of polio vaccine, and Rivers' Navy experience in the Pacific during World War II.
Rivers, Thomas M.(Thomas Milton),1888-1962.
Bibliography
Horshall, Frank L., "Thomas M. Rivers," Biographical Memoirs of the National Academy of Sciences 38 (1965), 262-294.
Shope, Richard E., Obituary of Thomas M. Rivers, Journal of Bacteriology 84 (1962), 385-388.
Rivers, Thomas, Tom Rivers, Reflections on a Life in Medicine and Science: An oral History Memoir (Cambridge, Mass.: MIT, 1967). Call no.: B R52b
Physiology, Biochemistry, and Biophysics Note
Thomas Milton Rivers came to the hospital of the Rockefeller Institute in 1922 with the aim of establishing a research program in the new field of viral diseases. During the following fifteen years Rivers conducted studies on chicken pox and on viruses which cause psittacosis, poliomyelitis, and lymphocytic choriomeningitis, and developed methods for producing a smallpox vaccine for use in children. When Rivers was made director of the Institute's hospital in 1937, he was a world authority on virus research, a field that was then undergoing rapid growth as part of the nascent molecular biology program. During his directorship (1937-1955), Rivers was an active coordinator of medical war projects, and a principal organizer of research programs within the National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis (N.F.I.P); the N.F.I.P. became a major pursuit after his retiring from the Institute.
Due to his prominence and wide range of administrative activities, Rivers' papers include correspondence with many leading researchers and administrators in the life sciences, especially with those in fields related to microbiology and molecular biology. However, the correspondence with individuals tends to be brief and formal, touching mainly on administrative concerns. Furthermore, because the collection begins in 1940, there is little of substance (apart from early laboratory notes) to document the earlier stage of Rivers' scientific career. However, the Flexner Papers contain records on Rivers' virus research, and on administrative aspects of his department and the hospital.
In spite of their limitations, the Rivers Papers are a valuable source in four areas: 1) the growth of American institutions of the life sciences in the postwar era, 2) biomedical war research and the Navy, 3) the development of virology, and 4) research on poliomyelitis and the development of the Salk vaccine.
American Public Health Association ( Potentially useful in documenting the growth of American institutions of the life sciences in the postwar era.) Correspondence (8 items) 1935-1960 English
Andrewes, C. H. (Christopher Howard), Sir ( Includes work entitled "Herpes virus nomenclature.") Correspondence (2 folders) 1950-1954 English
Armed Forces Epidemiological Board ( Documents biomedical war research and the Navy. Includes one folder on Projects and Proposals.) Records (4 folders) 1949-1953 English
Avery, Oswald Theodore, 1877-1955 Correspondence (1 item) 1946 English
Bawden, F. C. (Frederick Charles) Correspondence (2 items) 1952 English
Bronk, Detlev W. (Detlev Wulf), 1897-1975 Correspondence (19 items) 1946-1962 English
Burnet, F. M. (Frank Macfarlane), Sir, 1899-1985 Correspondence (2 items) 1952 English
Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944 Correspondence (3 items) 1938 English
Cohen, Seymour S. (Seymour Stanley), 1917- Correspondence (2 items) 1952 English
Cohn, Edwin J. (Edwin Joseph), 1892-1953 Correspondence (1 item) 1950 English
Conference on Inactivation of Viruses ( Potentially useful in documenting the development of virology.) Correspondence (1 item) Circa 1950-1959 English
Conference on Tissue Culture ( Potentially useful in documenting the development of virology.) Correspondence (1 item) 1952 English
Conference on Virus-Host Cell Relationships ( Potentially useful in documenting the development of virology.) Correspondence (1 item) 1948 English
Delbruck, Max Correspondence (2 items) 1943 English
Demerec, M. (Milislav), 1895-1966 Correspondence (2 items) 1953 English
Dubos, Rene J. (Rene Jules), 1901-1982 Correspondence (12 items) 1943-1962 English
Du Vigneaud, Vincent, 1901-1978 Correspondence (1 item) 1953 English
Gratia, Andre, 1893-1950 ( See folder Welsch, Maurice.) Correspondence (2 items) 1950 English
Gregg, Alan, 1890-1957 Correspondence (1 item) 1958 English
John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation ( Potentially useful in documenting the growth of American institutions of the life sciences in the postwar era.) Correspondence (2 items) 1940-1941 English
Hershey, A. D. (Alfred Day), 1908-1997 Correspondence (2 items) 1951 English
Hollaender, Alexander, 1898-1986 Correspondence (2 items) 1953 English
Horsfall, Frank Lappin, 1906-1971 Correspondence (13 items) 1937-1962 English
International Congress for Microbiology ( Potentially useful in documenting the development of virology. Materials from relating to the 4th international congress in Copenhagen (1947) and the congress in Stockholm (1958).) Records (2 folders) 1947, 1958 English
International Poliomyelitis Congress ( Research on poliomyelitis and the development of the Salk vaccine. Includes information on the 2nd (Denmark), 3rd (Rome), and 5th (Denmark) international congresses.) Correspondence (4 folders) 1949-1961 English
Luria, S. E. (Salvador Edward), 1912-1991 Correspondence (2 items) 1952 English
Lwoff, Andre, 1902-1994 Correspondence (1 item) 1960 English
National Academy of Sciences ( Potentially useful in documenting the growth of American institutions of the life sciences in the postwar era. Includes Facsimile of Original Signature Book, Presidency, Proposals for Nomination, and Section of Pathology and Microbiology.) Records (5 folders) 1946-1953 English
National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, Inc. ( Research on poliomyelitis and the development of the Salk vaccine. Includes National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, Inc. (9 folders); Committee on Diagnosis; Committee on Virus Research; Fellowships; Greater New York Chapter; March of Dimes; March of Dimes, Fulton-DeKalb Chapter; Specifications and Minimal Requirements for Polio Vaccine; Recommended Practices...and Questions and Answers About Polio; Vaccine Advisory Committee/Committee on Virus Research; Vaccine for Export; Vaccine Protocols.) Correspondence (21 folders) 1941-1962 English
National Institutes of Health ( Potentially useful in documenting the growth of American institutions of the life sciences in the postwar era. Includes folders entitled: History; Minimum Requirements, Polio Vaccine; and National Microbiological Institute.) Records (4 folders) 1952-1956 English
National Research Council ( Potentially useful in documenting the growth of American institutions of the life sciences in the postwar era. Includes folders on Division of Medical Services and Organization and Members.) Records (3 folders) 1944-1955 English
O'Connor, Basil, 1892-1972 ( Research on poliomyelitis and the development of the Salk vaccine.) Correspondence (7 folders) 1939-1962 English
Osterhout, W. J. V. (Winthrop John Van Leuven), 1871-1964 Correspondence (2 items) 1951 English
Public Health Research Institute ( Potentially useful in documenting the growth of American institutions of the life sciences in the postwar era.) Records (15 folders) 1941-1955 English
Rivers, Thomas M. (Thomas Milton), 1888-1962. History of U.S. Naval Medical Research Unit No. 2 ( Documents biomedical war research and the Navy. Includes two folders of plates and photographs.) Records (5 folders) 1945 English
Rivers, Thomas M. (Thomas Milton), 1888-1962. Manuscript materials concerning virus research ( Various folders of manuscript materials documenting viruses and virus research. See below for specific topics covered.) Correspondence (Approximately 25 folders) 1923-1960 English
Rockefeller Institute ( Potentially useful in documenting the growth of American institutions of the life sciences in the postwar era. Includes: Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (3 folders); By-Laws and Resolutions; Faculty and Student Club; Hospital, "Report of a Fire"; International Health Division; Minutes of Board Meetings (14 folders); Press; Public Relations; Report of the Hospital (3 folders).) Records (26 folders) 1922, 1949-1959 English
Sabin, Albert B. (Albert Bruce), 1906-1993 ( Research on poliomyelitis and the development of the Salk vaccine. Correspondence and folders entitled "The Herpes Group of Viruses, Recommendations for Classification" and "Present Status of a [Polio] Vaccine.") Correspondence (4 folders) 1953 English
Salk, Jonas, 1914-1995 ( Research on poliomyelitis and the development of the Salk vaccine. Three folders of correspondence plus the following folders: Critique of AMA Report on "Present State in U.S."; Critique...Summary Statement; Press Conference; Specifications and Minimal Requirements for Polio Vaccine; Polio Vaccine Preparation and Administration; Formaldehyde Treatment of Polio Vaccines.) Correspondence (9 folders) Circa 1954-1961, n.d. English
Stanley, Wendell M. (Wendell Meredith), 1904-1971 Correspondence (4 items) 1954-1962 English
Tatum, Edward Lawrie, 1909-1975. Importance of Basic Research Manuscripts (6 pages) 1959 English
Tiselius, Arne, 1902-1971 Correspondence (1 item) 1941 English
U.S. Department of Defense, Research and Development Board ( Documents biomedical war research and the Navy.) Correspondence (3 folders) 1948-1953 English
United States. Dept. of the Navy ( Documents biomedical war research and the Navy. Includes Bureau of Medicine and Surgery; Final Orders and USNR Papers for T.M. Rivers (2 folders); Miscellaneous World War II Memos; Rivers' Promotion to Rear Admiral.) Correspondence (6 folders) 1942-1955 English
Zinsser, Hans, 1878-1940 Correspondence (17 items) 1938-1940 English
Related Archival Materials note
The APS collections include several collections relating to Rivers' colleagues at the Rockefeller Institute, including Rufus Ivory Cole, Peyton Rous, James B. Murphy, and Oswald H. Robertson.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of the Rivers estate, 1971 (accession number 1971-332ms)
Scope and Contents note
Stilted toward the last twenty years of his life, the Rivers Papers document the late career and research of the virologist and medical administrator, Thomas Milton Rivers. The 10 linear feet of correspondence, manuscripts, and photographs are a valuable resource for understanding the institutionalization of medical research in the 1940s and 1950s, particularly at the Rockefeller and the National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, and for tracking the course of development of the polio vaccine in the early 1950s. Other than a sparse few research notebooks, there is little to document his research prior to the 1940s.
Rivers' military experience forms a leitmotif running throughout the collection. His service as head of Naval Medical Research Unit II in the South Pacific during the Second World War is documented through a small series of correspondence and other materials, primarily of an administrative nature, including a unit history written by Rivers in December 1945. There are nearly 200 photographs, more than half of which depict the research hospital in Guam and its personnel, and a smaller number of powerful photographs depicting members of the American military in Nagasaki, Japan, ca.1946, that provide graphic testimony to the devastation unleashed by the atomic bombing. Rivers' service with the Army Medical Corps during World War I is documented by a sparse set of official documents comprising a portion of his military record.
Biographical/Historical note
After a desultory education in Jonesboro, Georgia, Thomas M. Rivers discovered biology as an undergraduate at Emory College. With the encouragement of a biology professor, he entered medical school at Johns Hopkins in 1909, though a mysterious nervous degeneration (diagnosed as Aran-Duchenne atrophy) forced him to withdraw in the middle of his second year. Rivers made the most of his recovery, taking a position as a laboratory assistant at a hospital in Panama to gain clinical experience, and when his condition vanished as mysteriously as it had appeared, he returned to Hopkins, completing his MD in 1915.
Rivers' internship in pediatrics at the Johns Hopkins Hospital was interrupted by military service, an event that induced an unexpected, but important shift in his perspective. Entering the Army medical corps in 1918, Rivers was assigned to For Sam Houston, near San Antonio, Texas, to take part in a commission headed by Rufus Ivory Cole of the Rockefeller Institute, investigating concurrent outbreaks of measles and pneumonia. The experience awakened Rivers' interest in medical research, and when he returned to Hopkins at the end of his military obligations, he transferred into the Department of Bacteriology. In 1922, Cole invited Rivers to join the Institute and pursue research in the still poorly understood field of virology.
Between 1922 and 1955, Rivers molded Rockefeller into the preeminent laboratory for research on viruses, and in over 100 papers published during these years, Rivers addressed a range of topics relating to some of the most devastating viral diseases, including smallpox, Rift Valley Fever, and epidemic encephalitis. More importantly, he helped delineate the disciplinary boundaries of virology as both conceptually and methodologically distinct.
During the Second World War, Rivers again offered his services, serving as commander of the Naval Medical Research Unit in the South Pacific where his attentions were drawn to coordinating the effort to combat malaria and typhus. He eventually retired from the Navy with the rank of Rear Admiral. He returned to the Rockefeller in 1946, remaining for an additional ten years and eventually earning promotion to director of the institute (1953-1955).
In the last few years of his life, Rivers served as medical director of the National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, with which he had been associated since 1938, and as such, played a highly visible role in the development of the polio vaccine. He stepped down in 1958 to become Vice President for medical Affairs, remaining in that position until his death in 1962. Rivers was recognized for his work with election to the American Philosophical Society (1942) and the National Academy of Sciences (1932), and he served as president of the American Society for Clinical Investigation (1932), the Society of American Immunologists (1934), and the Society of American Bacteriologists (1936).
American Medical Association.; Andrewes, C.H. (Christopher Howard), Sir; Bayne-Jones, Stanhope, 1888-1970; Berry, George Packer, 1898-; Bronk, Detlev W., (Detlev Wulf), 1897-1975; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945; Chesney, Alan M., (Alan Mason), 1888-1964; Chinard, Francis P., 1918-; Cohn, Alfred E., (Alfred Einstein), 1879-1957; Cole, Rufus Ivory, 1872-1966; Corner, George Washington, 1889-1981; Dubos, René J. (René Jules), 1901-; Flexner, Simon, 1863-1946; Gasser, Herbert Spencer, 1888-1963; Hershey, A. D., (Alfred Day), 1908-; Jackson, Robert H.; Loeb, Jacques, 1859-1924; Long, Esmond R., (Esmond Ray), 1890-; National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis.; O'Connor, Basil, 1892-1972; Rockefeller Institute. Hospital; Rous, Peyton, 1879-1970; Sabin, Albert B., (Albert Bruce), 1906-; Salk, Jonas, 1914-1995; Welch, William Henry, 1850-1934; Atomic bomb--Japan--Nagasaki-shi; Laboratory notes; Medical administration; Medical sciences; Medicine, Military; Photographs; Poliomyelitis--Research; Poliomyelitis--Vaccination; Speeches.; United States. Navy. Naval Medical Research Unit II; Virology; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1939-1945
- Series I. Correspondence, 1941-1963; 9.5 linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Professional correspondence of Thomas M. Rivers from approximately the end of the Second World War until his death in 1963. Relating largely to his work with the National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, research on poliomyelitic more generally, and his administrative duties at the Rockefeller Institute, the series provides a valuable, but ultimately relatively limited perspective on Rivers's career.
  - Aaron, Harold (Box 1)
  - Abbott, Robert Tucker (Box 1)
  - Academy of Medicine of New Jersey (Box 1)
  - Ackerman, Steven J. (Box 1)
  - Ackermann, W W (Box 1)
  - Adams, John M (Box 1)
  - Advertising club of Baltimore (Box 1)
  - Advertising Council, Polio Conference Report (Box 1)
  - Ahrens, Edward H (Box 1)
  - Albert, Isaac (Box 1)
  - Albritton, Errett C (Box 1)
  - Alex, Stephan (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Hattie (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Rose (Box 1)
  - Alexandridis, Dimitrios (Box 1)
  - Alfs, Alfred (Box 1)
  - Alpha Omega Alpha (Box 1)
  - Amateis, Edmond (Box 1)
  - America Clinica (Box 1)
  - American Academy of General Practice (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Microbiology (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Pediatrics (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Pediatrics, Committee on Infectious Diseases (Box 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 1)
  - AAAS: Theobald Smith Award (Box 1)
  - American Association of Pathologists and Bacteriologists (Box 1)
  - American Board of Bio-Analysts (Box 1)
  - American Clinical and Climatological Association (Box 1)
  - American College of Hospital Administrators (Box 1)
  - American College of Physicians (Box 1)
  - American Committee for the Weizmann Institute of Science (Box 1)
  - American Cyanamid Company (Box 1)
  - American Epidemiological Society (Box 1)
  - American Heart Association (Box 1)
  - The American Institute (Box 1)
  - American Journal of Diseases of Children (Box 1)
  - American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene (Box 1)
  - American Medical Association (Box 1)
    - AMA: Committee on Medical Preparedness (Box 1)
    - AMA: Journal, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - AMA: Present Status of Polio Vaccination (Box 1)
    - AMA: Scientific Assembly, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - AMA: Standard Nomenclature (Box 1)
    - AMA: War Medicine (Box 1)
  - American Men of Medicine (Box 1)
  - American Men of Science (Box 1)
  - American Philosophical Society (Box 1)
  - American Public Health Association (Box 1)
  - American-Scandinavian Foundation (Box 1)
  - American Society for Microbiology (Box 1)
  - American Society of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene (Box 1)
  - American Women's Association (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Donald G (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Harold C (Box 1)
  - Anderson, William Willis (Box 1)
  - Andrewes, C H (Box 1)
    - Herpes virus nomenclature, Andrewes, C.H. (Christopher Howard), Sir
  - Andrews, E I (Box 1)
  - Angrist, Alfred (Box 1)
  - Animal Care Panel (Box 1)
  - Apgar, Virginia (Box 1)
  - Appleton, Charles W. (Box 1)
  - Archibald, R. M.
  - Armed Forces Epidemiological Board, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - AFEB: Projects, Proposals (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, Donald B (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, Mrs. Donald Budd (Box 1)
  - Asociacion para la Lucha contro la Paralisis Infantil (Box 1)
  - Association of American Medical Colleges (Box 1)
  - Association of American Physicians (Box 1)
  - Atlantic City, Convention Bureau (Box 1)
  - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission (Box 1)
  - Atoms for Peace Awards (Box 1)
  - Auersperg, Alfred P.V.A. (Box 1)
  - Avery, Oswald T (Box 1)
  - Ayerst, McKenna and Harrison (Box 1)
  - Aymond, Branch J (Box 1)
  - Aynes, Edith A (Box 1)
  - Bachman, M C (Box 1)
  - Bachmeyer, A C (Box 1)
  - Baehr, George (Box 1)
  - Baker, Rollin H (Box 1)
  - Bales, James D (Box 1)
  - Balfour, Donald C (Box 1)
  - Bang, Frederik B (Box 1)
  - Barger, Andrew (Box 1)
  - Barnard, Chester I (Box 1)
  - Barrett, C D et al. Modern Concepts of Immunizing... (Box 1)
  - Barrows, Howard S (Box 1)
  - Bates, Talcott (Box 1)
  - Batson, Randolph (Box 1)
  - Bauer, J. H (Box 1)
  - Bauer, Walter (Box 1)
  - Baumgartner, Leona (Box 1)
  - Bautista, Gonzalo (Box 1)
  - Bawden, F C (Box 1)
  - Bayne-Jones, Stanhope, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Bazeley, P. L (Box 1)
  - Bearcroft, W G C (Box 1)
  - Beaudette, F R (Box 1)
  - Beaudette, Thomas Rivers (Box 1)
  - Beckwith, W S (Box 1)
  - Bedson, S P (Box 1)
  - Beeson, Paul B (Box 1)
  - Behrman, Mrs. M H (Box 1)
  - Belgium, Consulate General (Box 1)
  - Belknap, Chauncey (Box 1)
  - Bell, A N (Box 1)
  - Beninson, Saul (Box 1)
  - Benyesh, Mathilda (Box 1)
  - Berger, Erick (Box 1)
  - Bergsma, D (Box 1)
  - Bernard, Nick (Box 1)
  - Berne, Fritzi F (Box 1)
  - Berry, George Packer (Box 1)
  - Bessey, Otto A (Box 1)
  - Beth Abraham Home for Incurables (Box 1)
  - Bieling, Professor (Box 1)
  - Bigger, Joseph W (Box 1)
  - Binger, Carl A L (Box 1)
  - Binkley, Francis (Box 1)
  - Biographical Encyclopedia of the World (Box 1)
  - Biondi, Laurie (Box 1)
  - Birchenough, Katherine (Box 1)
  - Birnkrant, Maxim (Box 1)
  - Birth Defects Study Center (Box 1)
  - Blackhurst, L R (Box 1)
  - Blagden, Mrs. Dexter (Box 1)
  - Blake, Francis Gilman (Box 1)
  - Blakely, Nancy P (Box 1)
  - The Blakiston Company (Box 1)
  - Blalock, Alfred (Box 1)
  - Bloch, Hubert (Box 1)
  - Blomquist, R Thomas (Box 1)
  - Bloom, William (Box 1)
  - Bloomfield, Arthur L (Box 1)
  - Blue Cross - Blue Shield (Box 1)
  - Bluemel, C S (Box 1)
  - Blum, Theodor (Box 1)
  - Bodian, David (Box 1)
  - Bohart, George (Box 1)
  - Bohart, R M (Box 1)
  - Boland, Frank K (Box 1)
  - Borek, A M (Box 1)
  - Boshian, G M: O Prirode Virusovi mikrobov. (Box 1)
  - Bosma, James F. (Box 1)
  - Boucher, Judy (Box 1)
  - Bowers, Ralph F (Box 1)
  - Boyd, Helen E W (Box 2)
  - Boyd, Montague L (Box 2)
  - Boyd, T E (Box 2)
  - Boyd, William C (Box 2)
  - Boyo, A E (Box 2)
  - Boys Brotherhood Republic (Box 2)
  - The Boy's Club of New York (Box 2)
  - Bradley, Stanley E (Box 2)
  - Branch, Harold (Box 2)
  - Brand, Erwin (Box 2)
  - Bray, Harry (Box 2)
  - Breakwater Hotel (Box 2)
  - Breed, Robert S (Box 2)
  - Brennemann, Joseph (Box 2)
  - Brennemann's Practice of Pediatrics (Box 2)
  - Brent, Mary L (Box 2)
  - Bright, Mrs. Mabel (Box 2)
  - Brockway, P Bruce, Jr. (Box 2)
  - Brodie, Maurice (Box 2)
  - Bronk, Detlev W (Box 2)
  - Bronner, Felix (Box 2)
  - Brook, John R (Box 2)
  - Brooke, Wallace S (Box 2)
  - Brooklyn Council for Social Planning (Box 2)
  - Brooks, Chandler McC (Box 2)
  - Brown, Gordon C (Box 2)
  - Brown, Gordon C: The Longevity of Immunity... (Box 2)
  - Brown, Kenneth H (Box 2)
  - Brown, Ray Hyer (Box 2)
  - Brunn, Harold (Box 2)
  - Bryan, Joseph M (Box 2)
  - Bryan, Walter S (Box 2)
  - Bryant, J Marion (Box 2)
  - Bryson, Vernon (Box 2)
  - Bucci, Harry (Box 2)
  - Buchthal, Fritz (Box 2)
  - Buddingh, G John (Box 2)
  - Buerki, Robin C (Box 2)
  - Burch, George E (Box 2)
  - Burgess, Perry (Box 2)
  - Burnet, Sir Macfarlane (Box 2)
  - Burney, L E (Box 2)
  - Burnham, Mrs. T L (Box 2)
  - Burwell, C Sidney (Box 2)
  - Cain, J C (Box 2)
  - Calder, Royall M (Box 2)
  - Caldwell, Guy A (Box 2)
  - Calhoun, Phinizy (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Thomas F. (Box 2)
  - Campos, Oswaldo P (Box 2)
  - Cannan, R Keith (Box 2)